I don't regret anything!
（ひなた）
後悔なんてしない　しちゃダメだ！
I can't!
Because...
だって—
what I did was definitely not wrong!
私のしたことは
絶対 間違ってなんか ない！
It's strange.
（零(れい)）不思議だ
Even after...
人は…
so much time has passed,
こんなにも時が過ぎたあとで…
something can save you,
全く違う方向から
嵐のように救われることがある
coming in like a storm from a completely different direction.
Hina.
（零）ひなちゃん
Thank you.
ありがとう
You are...
君は 僕の恩人だ
my savior.
約束する
I promise.
I'll stay with you.
僕がついてる
Rei...
零ちゃん…
（零）一生かかってでも
僕は 君に恩を返すよ
Even if it takes the rest of my life,
I'll pay you back.
The clouds adorning the setting sun whispered "It's gonna be your turn next" into my ear
But now that they've grown tired of just killing time I'm sure I'll just be their scapegoat
But I'm the king of my very own world
I can even run on top of water
I'm the egg who can put itself back together again after a fall
And can even go on to become an astronaut
I'm sure if I pick up all the beads that rained from the sky and gather them up
Then one day I'll finally be able to plant a flag which signifies my very own liberty
So I pull on my ripped jeans and fight back the tears the draft brings
I exhale a big gulp of air and then another 'cause I'm a boxer rising up again
You only get one chance to come back from the brink
So pound on that door you painted yourself
The colorful ink disperses into two paths
But you're the one who decides how your flower blooms
Small World
Sniff, sniff.
（あかり）はい　デザート
（クロちゃん）ニャ〜…
Here's dessert!
（あかり）
桐山(きりやま)君のお土産のサクランボだよ
It's the cherries that Kiriyama brought over.
（モモ）わあ！
Cherries!
サクランボだ！　ハハッ！
ウ〜ン！
Thank you, Kiriyama.
（ひなた）ありがとう 桐山君
Nom nom
（３人）ウ〜ン！
Delicious!
（ひなた）おいしい！
They smell sour.
（クロちゃん）
酸っぱいにおいニャ…
I'm not crazy about fruit.
（シロちゃん）果物は あんまり…
ウ〜ン…　ンンッ…
（モモ）ウ〜ン…
（あかり）あれ？　モモ 眠い？
Huh? Are you sleepy, Momo?
Maybe we should take a bath.
お風呂 入ろっか もう
ちょっと早いけど
It's a bit early for that, though.
じゃ ひなちゃん
指してみようか 将棋
So, Hina, do you want to try playing shogi?
Huh?
Shake
W-Will you go easy on me?
て… 手加減してくれる？
Shake
Huh?
（零）えっ？
あっ します　しますよ もちろん
Shake
Yes! Yes, of course!
あっ…
じゃ ２階でやってもらっていい？
Then would you take it upstairs?
I wanna play some more...
（モモ）まだ遊ぶ〜…
I'm going to give Momo her bath.
（あかり）
ちょっと モモ お風呂入れるから
* Kawamoto House's
changing room is
the living room.
* Kawamoto House's
changing room is
the living room.
* Kawamoto House's
changing room is
the living room.
零ちゃんと遊ぶ
I wanna play with Rei.
（ひなた）桐山君
ホントに それだけでいいの？
Kiriyama.
Are you sure that's all you need?
Kiriyama
Hina
Yeah.
Are you positive? Just this much?
Kiriyama
Hina
（ひなた）
ホントのホントに
これでいいの？
Kiriyama
Hina
Yeah.
All right!
よし！　これなら勝てるかも！
Then I might be able to win!
Apparently the first time in Hina's room...
Let's get started.
（零）じゃ 始めるね
（ひなた）うん！
Okay.
Huh?
（ひなた）えっ？
なんで ひなからじゃないの？
Why aren't I going first?
I thought you were going easy on me.
手加減してくれるんじゃ…
ああ…　駒落ち将棋は—
The player who has less pieces goes first in handicap shogi.
落とした側が先手っていう
決まりがあるんだよ
What? Oh, but...
え〜っ？　あっ でも…
うん　どうぞ
Okay. Go ahead.
Five Minutes Later
I-I lost.
ま… 負けました
Gloom
ああっ！　もっかい！
Again!
Gloom
Let's play again!
（零）もっかい やろう！
Hey, yo, pineapple, lalala, a strange magical fruit...
そうだ！
俺 玉(ぎょく)と金 ２枚でいいから！
I know! I'll play with only the king and a gold!
（２人）♪ふしぎな まほうのみ
Damn it!
くそ！
なんて下手くそなんだ 俺！
Why am I so bad at this?!
Oh. You're capturing my pawn at 5e?
（神宮寺(じんぐうじ)）おっと…
５五歩を取ってくるか
Good one.
やるねえ
（零）会長は
何だかんだ言って—
If anything, the chairman is skilled at making
his opponents look good and enjoy themselves.
相手に楽しく
花を持たせるのうまいし
Okay, here's a hint.
（横溝(よこみぞ)）はい
では ここでヒントです
大駒は？
With strong pieces, you...
B-Back off and then strike!
（男性）
は… 離して打て！
Correct.
正解
Yokomizo takes the time to amuse and teach even oddball players.
（零）横溝さんのは—
端(はた)の人間まで
愉快にさせてくれるし
It's great.
勉強になる
It's about communication, Kiriyama.
（横溝）
コミュニケーションだよ 桐山
何がしたいのか
何を考えているのかを想像して—
Imagine what your opponent is thinking and what they want to do.
Then get close to their feelings.
相手の気持ちに寄り添うことだ
In the waiting room before
his first shogi event.
相手を
よ〜く見ていることだ
Look at your opponent closely.
まあまあ 落ち着いて
気楽にいこう
Now, calm down, and let's take it easy.
Look at your opponent closely.
（横溝）相手をよく見ることだ
（零）よし…
Okay.
Stare
Thanks, Rei.
零ちゃん ありがとう
I think I'm starting to get the hang of it, so I should be okay for the next one.
ちょっと分かってきたから
次は大丈夫
I'm no match for her!
かなわない！　またしても
中学生に気を遣わせてしまった！
This junior high school student is consoling me again!
（ひなた）じゃ もっかいね
Okay, one more time.
What's the point of coming here to console her if she's the one consoling you, Kiriyama Rei?!
（零）
励ましに来たのに気を遣われて
どうする？　桐山零！
And suddenly, I felt a lump in my throat.
（零）そして ふと胸が詰まった
Over the years, how often has this girl smiled and
been considerate of other people's feelings like this?
この子は
一体 どれだけ たくさん—
こうやって
笑顔で気を遣ってきたんだろう
ひなちゃん
Hina.
Listen...
あのね
A little bit at a time is fine.
話してもらえるかな？
Will you tell me about what's happening at school?
ちょっとずつでいいから
学校のこと
Right now, I guess this is what it's like.
（ひなた）
今はね そんな感じ …かな
It's like everyone is looking from afar.
みんな 遠巻きに見てる感じ
Hina thought and thought,
slowly sharing bits and pieces with me.
（零）ひなちゃんは
ポツポツ ゆっくりと—
考え考え 話してくれた
Our groups are ordered by last name, but at lunch,
（ひなた）
名前順の班なんだけど—
お昼とか みんな
すごい硬くなってるの分かる
I can tell that everyone gets so stiff.
They hardly ever look at me.
みんな 私のほう あんまり見ない
It's like only my group is at a wake.
なんか こう…
ウチの班だけ お通夜みたい
And then the silence is suddenly broken by the loud laughter of the girls who bullied Chiho.
そこに—
ちほちゃんをいじめた子たちの
大きな笑い声がかぶってくるの
Their loud,
loud voices.
Their laughter.
It's like there's an invisible hierarchy within our class.
まるで なんか クラスの中に
見えない階級とかがあって—
And your ranking decides how loud you can laugh or how much freedom you're allowed in the classroom.
その階級に合わせて—
“どのくらい大きな声で
笑っていい”とか—
教室の中で どのくらい自由に
楽しそうに振る舞っていいかが—
決められてるみたいな
（零）ひなちゃんのクラスの風景
That's the atmosphere of Hina's class.
そして それは 多分—
I'm sure this is a story that everyone
has experienced at one time or another.
誰もが どこかで絶対に
感じたことのあるはずの物語
そんなもの
ホントは ないはずなのに
Something like that shouldn't even exist, but...
でも…　でも 確かにある
But it does.
It's been there ever since elementary school.
ずっとあった 小学校のころから
Hey, Kiriyama.
（ひなた）ねえ 桐山君
あれは何なの？　あの空気は
What is that?
That atmosphere.
Who's cool? Who's not cool?
誰が えらくて
誰が えらくないって
いつ どうやって決まるの？
誰が決めるの？
When and how is that decided?
Who decides it?
私たち みんな 同じ
ただの中学生のはずなのに
Even though we're all just junior high school students.
Even though we're all just human beings.
（ひなた）
ただの同じ人間のはずなのに
Silence
Distance
Cackle
Hahaha
Is that what she really said?
Cackle
Hahaha
（高師(たかし)）
ホントに そんなこと言ったの？
あんなの全然ダメダメ！
Cackle
Hahaha
What a loser!
Cackle
Hahaha
Chew
Cackle
Munch
Chew
Like I was saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Like I was
saying...
Munch
Chew
Isn't that nuts?
（高城）ヤバくない？
（笑い声）
Totally!
Thank you for the meal.
（ひなた）ごちそうさま
That's hilarious!
（高城）ウケるんですけど！
（笑い声）
Gloomy
Th-This feels so awkward.
（ひなた）き… 気まずい
Gloomy
（高橋(たかはし)）川本(かわもと)いる？
（ひなた）た… 高橋君？　アア…
Is Kawamoto here?
T-Takahashi?
ギャ〜ッ！
Sting
痛い痛い 痛い痛い…
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Sting
（高橋）えっ ウソ！
俺 超そっと投げたけど
No way.
Sting
I totally threw that lightly.
（高橋）桐山さんに聞いた
（ひなた）えっ？
I heard from Kiriyama.
Huh?
（高橋）昼休みとか
困ったら キャッチボールしよう
At lunch time,
if things get difficult, let's just play catch.
２人じゃヤだったら
野球部のダチも呼ぶし
If you want more people,
I could call my baseball team buddies to join in.
They're already staring.
もう超見てるし
A girl!
（野球部員Ａ）女子だ！
Damn you, Takahashi! This is outrageous!
（野球部員Ｂ）
おのれ 高橋！　けしからん！
Kiriyama came over to my house yesterday to coach us.
（高橋）昨日さ—
桐山さん
うちに指導対局に来てくれたんだぜ
Oh, I see. Now I've got it.
（高橋の父親）おお そうか！
分かったぞ　４三銀には３四歩か
In response to S-4c, you play P*3d.
Professional shogi players are so amazing.
（高橋の祖父）ほんに すごいのぅ
プロ棋士さまはのぅ
That's why you're a professional.
さすがじゃのぅ
Yeah.
（高橋）うん…　あっ なるほど
（零）まあ 奇襲なんですけど
I see.
Well, it's a surprise tactic.
Dad and Grandpa were delighted.
（高橋）親父(おやじ)も じいさんも
すげえ喜んじゃってさ
Grandpa's been staying in bed recently, but he was up and about for this.
じいちゃんなんて
このところ 寝込んでたのに—
飛び起きてきてさ
（高橋）
またカレー呼んでよ 唐揚げの
Invite me over again for curry.
With the fried chicken.
この間
桐山さん 親父たちに取られて—
Last time Dad and Grandpa were hogging Kiriyama, so I couldn't really to talk to him.
しゃべれなかったんだよ 俺
Sure.
That hurts!
いった〜い！
（泣き声）
How could that hurt?
Small World
（高橋）痛くねえし
Letter
（棋士Ａ･零）
ありがとうございました
Thank you for the match.
Oh, thank you.
（職員）
あっ ありがとうございます
Good match today, Kiriyama, 5-dan.
（職員）お疲れさまです 桐山五段
（零）お疲れさまです
Thank you.
Clench
これで４勝！　しゃ！
That's four wins!
Yes!
Just one more and I'll be in the Shogi Maestro Tournament preliminary semifinals!
あと１回 勝てば
棋匠戦(きしょうせん)予選 準決勝！
Yeah! Things are looking up this month!
うん！　今月は調子いいぞ！
Right now, I've got two consecutive wins in class-promotion tournaments.
（零）順位戦は 今のところ ２連勝
I'm still in the running for Shogi Maestro Tournament,
the Lion King Tournament, and the Rookie Tournament.
トーナメントは
勝ち残れているのが—
棋匠戦 獅子王戦 新人戦
I'd like to win the Lion King Tournament.
獅子王戦には勝ちたいな
If I can win in group five and participate in the challenger tournament,
５組で優勝して
挑戦者決定トーナメントに出て…
then I'll hit my financial target!
そしたら 目標額に食い込める！
でもって 新人戦…
But with the Rookie Tournament,
prize money aside, I want to win one more match, get to the finals, and build up momentum.
賞金は ともかく
これは あと１回 勝って—
決勝まで なんとしても行って
勢いをつけたい
よし 練習だ！
ぜってえ負けねえ！
All right, I need to practice.
I'm not going to lose!
新人王に 俺はなる！
I'll become the Rookie King!
School Zone
（生徒たち）おはよう
Good morning.
Good morning!
Stop flirting
around, moron
ハァ…
さすがに食べきれなかった…
これが“胃が痛い”ってやつかな
I couldn't finish eating everything.
Is this what they call a stomachache?
（殴る音）
ウワッ！
なんで来ねえんだ？
Why didn't you show up?
T-Takahashi!
た… 高橋君
（高城）ビッチ
Slut.
Um, thanks, Takahashi.
え〜っと…　高橋君 ありがとう
But today, I...
でも 私 今日は…
Uh, I think we were in the same class in first year.
え〜っと 確か
１年んとき 同じクラスだった…
（高橋）おい 高城
（高城）ンッ…
Hey, Takagi.
That's your name, right?
（高橋）…だったよな？
お前もさ 一緒にやんねえ？
You want to play catch too?
いくぞ！　用意 いいか？
Here I go!
You ready?
（木村(きむら)）メグから やんなよ
（高城）ウソ！　怖い〜！
You go first, Megu!
No way! I'm scared!
（高師）大丈夫だって！　ほら！
（高橋）いくよ！
It'll be fine! Go on!
Here I go!
And... go!
せ〜の！
Jerk! You suck!
最低！　バ〜カ！
I'm out of here! That guy's insane!
知らない！
どうかしてんじゃないの？
Megu, wait!
メグ 待ってよ！
Huh?
（高橋）あれ？
なに？　もう行っちゃうの？
What, you're leaving already?
Hey, what's wrong?
おい！　どうしたんだ？
（ひなた）
高橋君…　あ… あわわ…
Takahashi...
Y-Yikes.
高橋君
Takahashi.
They tossed my glove on the ground and ran off.
（高橋）あいつらめ
グローブ放っぽって逃げやがって…
The girl who changed schools was Sakura Chiho, right?
転校したのってさ
佐倉(さくら)ちほだったんだな
Huh?
（高橋）２年の移動教室んときさ
風 強くてさ—
During the overnight field trip in second year,
the wind blew my lunch box over and sand got all over my food.
俺 弁当のおかず ひっくり返して
砂まみれにしてさ
したら あいつ
自分の弁当 半分くれたんだよな
She gave me half of her's.
（高橋）笑ってさ “どうぞ”って
She said, "Here," with a smile.
自分の食い物くれるなんて
いいヤツだって思った
At the time, I thought that anyone who
shared their own food was a good person.
So let's play catch anytime.
だから キャッチボールは
いつでも やろうぜ
なんかさ
見せといたほうがいい気がする
I kind of feel like it's a good idea to
show them that there are allies too.
味方がいるってこと
（零）そっか…　でもって…
I see.
That said...
I'm sorry!
ごめん！
高橋君 カッコイイもんな
Takahashi is so handsome, huh?
I get it.
そうか　やっかみか…
Now they're envious.
I'm so sorry.
ホントに ごめん
そこまで気が回らなくて
I didn't think that far ahead.
There are bad people.
（クロちゃん）だめな人がいるニャ
No good.
（ミケちゃん）だめだニャ
（シロちゃん）うん　だめニャ
Yeah. Bad.
ああっ！
違うの 桐山君　そうじゃなくて
No, Kiriyama! Don't take it like that!
I'm going to keep playing catch.
キャッチボールは続けるよ 私
だって 楽しいし
After all, it's fun.
And Takahashi seems to remember Chiho.
それにね 高橋君が
ちほちゃんのこと覚えててくれて
そして 話せて…　うれしい
So I can talk about her, and that makes me really happy.
（ひなた）
もうクラスで 誰も ちほちゃんの
話とか しなくなってて
Nobody talks about Chiho in class anymore,
so it's like she was never there in the first place.
まるで なんか 最初から
いなかったことみたいになってて
（ひなた）
人ひとり いなくなったのに—
One person has gone away.
So why do they act like that?
“どうして”って
Huh? Sorry.
（ひなた）
えっ？　えっ？　あれ？　ごめん
（零）はい…　ほら
Here. Take this.
Rei, thank you for always listening to me.
零ちゃん　いつも
私の話 聞いてくれて ありがとう
You're always asking me what I want to do.
いつも“ひなちゃんは
どうしたい？”って聞いてくれて
Junior High School
But I...
（ひなた）でも 私…
（ひなた）
どうしたいのか分からなくて…
I don't know what I want to do,
so it's frustrating!
（ひなた）私は悔しい！
（ひなた）“どうしたい”って…
What do I want to do?
I want to yell "Idiots!" and punch them!
あいつら全部
“バカ”って叫んで 殴りたい！
I want to beat the crap out of them!
メチャメチャにしてやりたい！
I want to do to them what they did to Chiho!
ちほちゃんと同じ目に
遭わせてやりたい！
And then...
それで—
I want them to realize what they did!
自分たちが何したかを
思い知らせてやりたい
But it's too late.
でも もう遅い
ちほちゃんは もういない
Chiho's already gone!
（零）ちほちゃんに手紙を出したが
待っても 返事は来なかった
She sent Chiho a letter,
but a reply never came.
Instead, she received a response
代わりに届いたのは
彼女のお母さんからの手紙だった
Chiho hasn't gone back to school,
even after moving here.
Right now she's in rehab with a counselor
at a place called "Heart Care Center."
Chiho would like to write to you,
but I'm not sure she's able yet.
from Chiho's mother.
Besides, it's impossible!
Chiho hasn't gone back to school,
even after moving here.
Right now she's in rehab with a
（ひなた）
それにムリ　謝らせようにも…
now she's in rehab with a counselor
at a place called "Heart Care Center."
Chiho would like to write to you,
but I'm not sure she's able yet.
Even if I make them apologize,
Chiho would like to write to you,
but I'm not sure she's able yet.
ちほちゃんは もう—
I don't think Chiho would ever want to see their faces!
あいつらの顔なんて
見たくもないと思う
Kawamoto
Hinata
loves
guys
Pervert
Slut
Idiot
There's one thing that I realized.
（零）気づいたことが ひとつある
（零）僕は思ってたんだ
I'd thought...
that if things got tough, you could just get up and leave.
つらすぎるのなら
そこから立ち去っていい
That when someone treated you poorly,
（零）まともじゃないことを
してくるヤツらには—
you had to respond in kind.
まともに立ち向かうことは
しなくていい
でも…
But...
Stand up!
（男子生徒）起立
Bow!
（男子生徒）礼！
（担任）アア…
Kawamoto
Hinata
loves
guys
Kawamoto
Hinata
loves
guys
Pervert
Slut
Idiot
Huh?
Wh—
Kawamoto
Hinata
loves
guys
Kawamoto
Hinata
loves
guys
Idiot
K-Kawamoto, what's the meaning of this?
か… 川本さん
これは どういうことなの？
分かりません
書いたのは 私じゃありません
I don't know.
I'm not the one who wrote it.
Sakura Chiho
Absent
I think you're misreading it, Kawamoto.
（担任）
川本さんの勘違いじゃない？
You shouldn't always assume the worst of a situation.
そんな…
何でも悪いほうに取っちゃダメダメ
It was already written on the board when I came in this morning.
朝来たら もう書かれてました
A-Anyway, let's begin the lesson.
と… とにかく授業始めます
Kawamoto, please see me in the faculty office after class.
川本さんは あとで職員室へ
Come on, concentrate!
（担任）
はい 集中！　ザワザワしない！
Stop your whispering!
Let's have a good match.
（棋士Ｂ･零）
よろしくお願いします
That's right.
（零）そうだ　彼女は—
She's not only in pain.
ただ つらがっているんじゃない
She's angry.
怒っているのだ
In fact,
それも
腹の底から煮えくり返るほどに
she's seething from the pit of her stomach.
Letter
I wonder why I'm smiling
The night wears on as I trace it with a finger
In the oversized nooks of this world
My heart continues to melt away
Like the petals of a flower repelling the rain yet refusing to wither
All the things important to me have spilled out
Before I knew it I was all alone and I'd walked a great distance
I'd forgotten what my own voice really sounded like
And it was the strangest feeling
After dawn broke on that long night
I remembered as if it were all a dream
I gave myself up to that nostalgic eternity
And it seems like I can go on walking again
Next Episode Preview
Episode 29
No, don't look at me!
（ひなた）
イヤだ！　見ないで！
Sis, get me a towel!
お姉ちゃん
バスタオル取って！
What should I do?
（あかり）
どうしましょう！
母校が火の海に！
My alma mater will be
engulfed in a sea of flames!
At last! At last, we made it this far.
（二海堂(にかいどう)）ついに…
ついに ここまで来たな
I'm the only one at
our house who can go.
（あかり）
うちは 私しか
行く人間 いないもんね
I bought some peaches.
（零）桃 買ってきたよ
But maybe ice cream
would've been better.
でも アイスのほうが
よかったかな
Illustration: Amano Kozue
Yoohoo, yoohoo, cherries!
（あかり）♪ヤッホー
ヨーホー サクランボ
（モモ）♪ルルル
おいしい まほうのみ
Derere, yummy magical fruit!